These plans for after graduation...
Rio's the only one who didn't write anything.
Where is it that you want to go, Rio?
My parents' homeland, the Yagumo region.
Seirei Gensouki
Kingdom of Lies
As you already know,
magic uses formulae designed
to control magical power.
By pouring od through them, this craft
meddles with matters of the world.
Today, the fifth and
sixth-years will use Lighting
to deepen their understanding
of controlling magical power.
Lighting?
Professor! Anyone in this room should
be able to use low-level magic like—
No, wait.
There is one person who can't use it.
Yes, there is!
A lecture intended for those
with poor magic control...
Isn't it a little late for all of that?
I see.
Well then, will you two
try using Lighting for me?
Yes, Miss!
Lighting!
At that level, I can't say
you've mastered it yet.
What do you mean?
Being able to cast a covenant formula
depends on a person's affinity.
It's not the same as being
skillful in magical control.
Even without the use of magic,
with the existence of artifacts,
there are those who can use multiple
magical techniques simultaneously.
Like this.
Dectet Magician.
Lighting.
That's amazing!
One person can control that
many Lightings at once?!
It's true that I can't cast magical
covenant formulae like they can.
But...
by imitating the flow of magical power,
for some reason I'm able to
reproduce magical techniques.
All right!
Now, let's begin our lecture
on magical control!
Just what I'd expect from you,
Professor Celia!
I found that so moving!
Why, thank you.
Hey, commoner.
It seems you've been seducing
the female students of late.
What do you mean?
Don't flatter yourself.
Your win in the tournament
was simply a fluke.
I understand completely.
Then stop trying to push yourself forward.
Stewart, stop that, now.
You're of the nobility, aren't you?
You shouldn't lay criticism
without definite evidence.
B-But... this brat even
tries flirting with you!
Nothing of that sort has ever happened.
Hey, commoner.
If you try anything foolish
during the outdoor practicum,
the house of Duke Huguenot
will not stay silent!
Sir Rio...
Flora?
It's just...
That was clearly a false accusation, wasn't it?
Yes.
But not getting involved
is best for all of us.
I'm sure he understands that, too.
Oh, but...
He is always taking care of
things on his own like that.
And I still haven't been able
to do anything to repay him.
This is where our outdoor practicum
is being held, isn't it?
Yes.
They're going to test how well we've
learned military exercises at the academy.
I'm a little nervous.
There is no need to worry.
It's a team competition, and all the most
dangerous monsters have been culled.
Now, I will tell you the details
of the practicum from the notice.
In order to withdraw from
a battle zone, our units
will travel the shortest course through
this mountain forest and aim for the goal.
The operation lasts until sunset.
Good results here will have a tremendous
impact on all of our grades.
My friends, let's reach the
goal by this afternoon!
Yeah!
Won't that be impossible?
This is a wooded, mountainous area.
It will take twice as
long to travel anywhere.
Not to worry.
I've already got a special course in mind.
What do you mean?
The soldiers who serve in my home region
just happened to be quite knowledgeable
about the geography of this area.
I had them tell me about all the animal
paths that can be used as shortcuts.
Then I passed it on to our upperclassmen.
It feels like cheating. I don't like it.
To say that information controls
everything in war is no exaggeration.
We're practically guaranteed
a good result here.
What do you think, Princess Christina?
I'll leave it to you.
After all, you are the
commander of this unit.
Thank you.
Then, let's move out!
Yeah!
Hey, commoner.
Consider yourself honored.
You're a hindrance who can't even use magic,
but we've prepared a job
that even you can do.
This is everyone's luggage.
Carry it and follow us.
Understood.
Don't you dare do anything uncalled for.
Excuse me.
Um...
Shall I carry a little of that?
What?
No, I'm fine.
Thank you for your concern.
This just isn't right.
Why is it only Sir Rio
who must endure such...
Monsters!
Don't panic, everyone! They're goblins!
The three in the vanguard should use
artifacts to boost their physical abilities.
Charge!
Enchant Physical Ability!
They were nothing much.
We need more formidable monsters.
Just as I'd expect from you, Stewart.
You're so reliable.
By way of contrast...
Hey, Rio!
Don't just stand there in a daze!
My apologies.
That was much too close. To think anyone
would notice at this distance...
What an impossible child.
Shall we test him a little and
see what his true capabilities are?
We're out of the forest!
The goal is close!
All right! Hooray!
A cliff?
It can't be!
What's going on?
Maybe his information was wrong?
What are we going to do?
Go back the way we came?
We'd lose a lot of time.
Commander.
Y-Yes?
Where do we head next?
The path seems to come to an end here.
Well... That's...
Th-There are orcs!
Everyone! Defenses!
V-Vanguard!
Raise shields and block the spears!
Ow! It hurts! It hurts!
Help me...
Stop it!
Flora!
Sir Rio?
We need to focus on exterminating
the monsters first!
D-Defend!
Vanguard, raise shields and form a wall.
Rear guard, use attack magic
to lay down a barrage!
Roanna, tend to the injured!
Blitz Shot!
I wonder if falling from there without
a single injury will make them
suspicious of me.
I saved her without thinking about it.
It isn't magic or magical techniques.
Even now, I don't know what
this power actually is...
Or anything about that girl.
You can't be serious!
You say I pushed
Princess Flora off the cliff?!
No, I wouldn't go so far as that.
It's just that Alphonse asked me if anyone
might have bumped into Princess Flora.
I was pushed, too!
I am a victim here!
Someone else is responsible!
Getting overexcited isn't
good for your wounds.
And after I treated them for you, too.
Stewart, please, calm down.
I'm simply trying to understand
the circumstances.
Th-That's right! I've just remembered.
It's that commoner who's responsible!
Did you just...
Yes.
In that moment, the coward was so
frightened of the monsters' attack that,
though I am injured, he pushed
me with all his might!
Because of that, I could not avoid
colliding with Princess Flora!
So, fearful of committing the crime of
killing a member of the royal family,
that man may have saved
Princess Flora in his desperation,
but in return, he fell from the cliff himself?
Th-That can't be what happened!
Sir Rio was simply trying
his hardest to save me!
This has gotten problematic.
What should I do?
He's the one responsible.
Right, my upperclassmen?
Y-Yes.
Is this really the time to
be looking for a culprit?
Commander!
Th-Then, as Her Highness
the Princess is safe,
let's find a way out of the forest!
I had planned to graduate
from the academy, but...
Please, wait!
Are you saying we're
going to abandon Sir Rio?
That fall was just him
getting what he deserves.
Getting what he deserves?
Then my nearly falling was
me getting what I deserved.
I am going to go help Sir Rio,
even if I have to go alone!
You mustn't!
What are you saying, Princess Flora?
Flora, calm down.
As soon as this practicum is over,
we'll send out a search party!
Why is a monster like that...
Why are you just standing there?
We'll be killed!
Thunder Ball!
Wha—
If Thunder Ball doesn't work,
we need to use Ice Lance!
Vanguard, increase your physical abilities!
Ice Lance!
Enchant Physical Ability!
Re...
Retreat!
Run!
Princess Christina!
Please get a hold of yourself!
Of course...
Where is Flora?
I believe she has already escaped.
We should hurry as well.
Are you all right?
No!
Please, take him and get away from here!
Sir Rio!
Hurry!
Right!
This way!
Come on!
He's tough.
And...
He's fast!
I can't die here.
So why did I come back to save her?
He's amazing!
Now.
Why was that monster—
Princess Flora!
Princess Flora, are you hurt?
No. I'm s-so sorry!
My. I got to witness something even
more entertaining than I'd expected.
That black hair...
Is he the offspring of people who drifted
here from the Yagumo region, I wonder?
If so, I can see why he'd be
able to use the spirit arts.
What a worrisome child.
Honestly!
The Head of the Academy
is such a taskmaster!
You could just do the
research yourself, you know!
And these materials on monsters are so old...
And so, that commoner...
Rio has gone missing.
But Princess Flora is
advocating for this... Rio.
Lord Garcia,
if the standing of the
House of Huguenot is put at risk,
it will only embolden
the house of Duke Arbor.
That would be bad for the kingdom,
would it not?
The royal family has become weak.
It's maddening!
Now that things have come to this, I suppose
we have no choice but to blame the boy.
I'll leave the rest to you,
Duke Huguenot.
Understood.
Please leave the matter to me hereafter.
Rio...
What could have happened?
Who's there?
It's Rio.
I'm sorry for causing such a commotion.
P-Professor...
I was really worried!
I'm sorry.
Are you hurt? Are you all right?
That tickles!
That's horrible. What are they thinking?
They're laying a false charge!
Rio, you haven't done anything wrong!
It's the people in power who
decide what's wrong or not.
Even if I appealed with the truth,
no one would acknowledge it.
It's because I'm not of the nobility.
I'm sorry.
The truth is, I wish I could do
something about this for you, but...
Please, don't apologize.
Everything is thanks to you, Professor.
It's thanks to you
that I've been able to come this far
without crumbling and going bad.
I'm glad I was able to meet you, Professor.
I truly mean that.
Rio...
That's why you were the one person
I wanted to say goodbye to, Professor.
You're going to the Yagumo region, aren't you?
Yes.
I see.
I wanted to see you graduate, but...
I'll write you letters along the way.
Though I'll be using an alias.
All right. What name will you use?
Haruto.
Haruto...
Well then, I should be going.
I'll see you again, won't I?
Yes. I'm sure we'll meet again.
For certain, absolutely certain, understand?
Stay safe...
until you return... all right?
Have a safe trip!
I will! I'm off!
Your letters... I'll be waiting for them.
I'll be waiting, okay?
What is your name?
I'm called Celia.
Rio...
Rio? That's an unusual name.
My parents were immigrants.
Are you all right?
Don't touch me...
Just a moment. I'll make us some space.
There are a lot of
difficult-looking books here.
But you look so young, Professor.
Hm? Oh, yes.
I'm still only twelve, after all.
It's very good.
I'm glad you like it!
When you drink a good cup of tea...
It just makes you feel happy, doesn't it?
I have you, Professor Celia.
Huh?
What?
Oh, Rio!
Yes?
You're making fun of me, aren't you?
Treating me like a child!
But you're older than me, Professor.
Y-Yes, but... well... it means you
think of me as a friend, right?
Yes.
Would you rather I didn't?
I... don't mind.
What?
That is the clothing of
the assassination target.
Remember the scent.
The target is twelve years old
and male. Goes by Rio.
His hair is black, so you
should recognize him quickly.
No matter what it takes,
find him and kill him,
Latifa.
Understood.
Next Time
Little Assassin Girl
"Little Assassin Girl."
Spirit Chronicles
Exciting Bonus Manga
I'm Flora.
By Minazuki Futago
I wanted
to thank
him...
...for
saving
me so
many
times.
Do you
have any
idea...
...where
Sir Rio
is right
now?
N-No?
She's
surprisingly
sharp...